MARYANNE CHEPKORIR

SEO Specialist/Digital Marketer

With a strong foundation in sales, refined analytical skills, and an ever-growing passion for SEO and digital marketing, I'm primed to make a significant impact in the digital landscape. My goal is to create immersive online experiences that captivate audiences, enhance brand visibility, and drive organic growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Globeflight Kenya - Digital Marketing/SEO Specialist (February 2023-October 2023)

- Conducting precise keyword research, on-page optimizations, and backlink strategies to achieve impressive organic rankings in the logistics industry
- Crafting engaging, SEO-optimized blog content and devised content marketing strategies for enhanced visibility.
- Creating Google Ads campaigns, social media strategies, and email marketing for lead generation • Google Analytics and ROI.
- Leveraging data analytics for informed decision-making and A/B testing for conversion rate optimization.
- Collaborating closely with clients, delivering captivating SEO presentations and workshops.
- Transforming website, driving traffic, and generating leads, forging lasting client relationships built on trust.
- Enhancing website performance through technical SEO improvements and audits.
- Crafting social media/Email copies and performance marketing strategy
- Optimizing PPC campaigns, reducing costs and maximizing returns.

Career Transition- Oct 2022-Dec 2022

I transitioned to SEO and digital marketing, where i used my skills to optimize websites for better search engine visibilityby gradually increasing site traffic

Sky Garden, August 2020 - September 2022 **Commercial Project Manager & Key Account Mngr:**

- Led high-performing teams, ensuring project success and client satisfaction.
- Strategically managed key accounts, driving revenue growth through innovative solutions.
- Excelled in negotiation, contract management, and cross-functional collaboration.
- Consistently met and exceeded sales targets while minimizing attrition.
- Proactively identified and mitigated business risks,

fostering transparency.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Jumia Kenya (Jan 2019 - March 2020)

Vendor Acquisition

CONTACT

- Kenya- +254706724909
- maryannemutaic@gmail.com

Hard SKills:

- Digital Media
- Instagram Growth
- Email Marketing
- Content Management
- SEM
- PPC Advertising

Tools and Software:

- Google Analytics
- Hootsuite & Hubspot
- Semrush & Ahrefs
- Asana & slack

EDUCATION

Muranga University Bachelor of Science Procurement and supply chain management 09/2014 - 08/2018

Udemy-Beginner SEO to Advanced SEO-OCT 2022

My Portfolio

Blogs-Wrote different blogs stories on different topics

https://shorturl.at/duDO7

https://shorturl.at/cjxGQ

https://raymuraya.com/becoming-ray-muraya/ **SEO**-Optimising user experience and website ranking for

Globeflight -https://globeflight.co.ke/

REFERENCES

- Brenda Waithera-0700564924(Head of Marketing Globeflight Kenya)
- Eric Mutisya-0724963750(Head of commercial Operations Skygarden)